rootusers.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - RootUsers

## Privacy Policy of www.rootusers.com

This website collects some personal data from its users.

### Google and third-party advertising cookies

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to our website or to other websites on the Internet. These third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browser, or using web beacons to collect information as a result of ad serving on this website. You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). The cookies of other [third-party vendors or ad networks](https://support.google.com/dfp_sb/answer/94149) may also be used to serve ads on this website. You may visit those vendor and ad network websites to opt out of the use of cookies for personalized advertising (if the vendor or ad network offers this capability). Alternatively, you can opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

www.rootusers.com uses Google AdSense, which is an advertising service provided by Google. Adsense uses the [DoubleClick cookie](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090?hl=en), which tracks use of www.rootusers.com and user behavior concerning ads, products and the services we offer. You can find the [AdSense Privacy Policy here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/).

This website also uses Google Analytics, which collects cookies and usage data.

### Amazon Associates Program

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated sites.

### Contacting the user

This website allows visitors to sign up to our mailing list by providing their email address. No other user information is provided when signing up to the mailing list. Once you submit your email address, you will receive an email requiring you to confirm that you wish to join the mailing list.

The mailing list is only used to send notifications of new posts that have been published on this website. The list of email addresses is maintained by wordpress.com, a third-party service that this WordPress based website integrates with. You can opt-out of future communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe button found in every email.

### Content commenting

This website allows users to comment on any page. In doing so, the name and email fields are required so that we can see who the comment is from. You can also optionally submit your website URL if you have one. When submitting a comment you can optionally select if you want to receive email updates to the comment If you selected to receive these notifications, you can opt-out of these messages by clicking the unsubscribe link found in the email.

Along with the comment text itself, this user submitted information for comments is stored in our database on the rootusers.com web server. The data is only used when responding to a user’s comment and is not distributed or used for any other purpose. You may request that your comment be removed at any time, which will delete all associated user submitted information.

### Log Files

Every page view to this website is logged on the web server and stored for 180 days. If you accessed this website by clicking a link on another external website, this address is logged in the referrer header. Additionally the IP address that you access this website from is also logged, along with the date and time of the visit. This information is not distributed to anyone else and is only referred to if needed, for instance to investigate unauthorized access attempts to the website.

### Changes to this privacy policy

Please note that this privacy policy is subject to change without any prior notice to the user. This may happen at any time. Should this privacy policy be updated, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. Rootusers.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its privacy policy, and we will include a change log outlining what has changed with each update.

Last update to the privacy policy for www.rootusers.com: **May 18th 2017**
